Guide to the Paul Ceruzzi papers, 1990s-2000s
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
Paul Ceruzzi papers
1990s-2000s
C0306
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
6.0 linear feet (22 boxes)
The Paul Ceruzzi Papers contain Paul Ceruzzi's research done while writing his book "Internet Alley: High Technology in Tysons Corner, 1945-2005." It also contains some materials concerning the development of the area after the publishing of the book.
Ceruzzi, Paul
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Biographical Note
Paul Ceruzzi is Curator of aerospace and electronics at the National Air and Space Museum in Washington D.C. Dr. Ceruzzi attended Yale University and the University of Kansas, acquiring his PhD in American Studies in 1981. He has authored or co-authored several books in addition to "Internet Alley," such as "Computing, A Concise History" and "Beyond the Limits: Flight Enters the Computer Age," among many others.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Paul Ceruzzi in June 2017.
Scope and Content
This collection is an extensive gathering of local Fairfax County history as it relates to the development of computational technology in the Northern Virginia region. There is a lot of military history from the Cold War, weapons development programs, as well as the development of the public face of the Internet. Dr. Ceruzzi's research ranged from the development of Tysons Corner as a small hamlet to the bustling office and shopping center it eventually became. His work collected here shows the many aspects of Northern Virginia that were involved not only in the growth of the Internet and the local region as a suburb of D.C. but also the constant presence of military and government officials, some less subtle than others. The collection is made up of research papers, declassified military intelligence documents, research done by the various contractor corporations that were drawn to the region, and interviews with prominent individuals, such as Til Hazel and George Johnson, former president of George Mason University. Also included were several empty folders, which have been removed from the collection. The titles of these folders were "NSFnet, circa 1995," "Radio Tower" and "Tower Pix."
The collection is made up of papers, photographs, maps, and newspapers.
Arrangement
Arranged mostly alphabetically, kept in original order.
Related Material
The Special Collections Research Center also holds the papers of other Northern Virginia development projects, including several on Reston, such as the and the, as well as several others.
Index Terms
Persons:
Hazel, Til.; Johnson, George W., 1928-2017
Geographical Names
Virginia, Northern--History, Local.; Virginia, Northern--Maps.
Subjects:
Cold war.; Military intelligence--United States.; Technology.; Zoning--Virginia--Fairfax.
Contents List
  - Photos for Washington History, 1957, 1970s-2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - VU-graphs for Beltway Task, 1950s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Tysons Aerial Photos, 1960s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photos - Mathys 1980s, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - SHFG Pix, 1967, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - List of Illustrations July 2004, 1999-2004 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Geography 1990s, 2000-2003 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Early Reston, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Tysons Corner MLK Library, 1967-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Aerial Photos, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Captions, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Illustrations 8/05, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Tysons Remodeling, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Tysons Corner Photo VA Room, 1956-circa 1980s (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Permissions, Virginia Room, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Tysons Photos, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 16)
    range from 1930s-1980s
  - Pentagon 2.1, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Photo Captions, circa 2000s (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Tysons Corner Workshop, February-March 2007 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 8: RUF, January 2007 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - ASAP, January 2007 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Tysons USGS Maps, 1970s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Maps Final May 2007 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Auto Railer, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - SHOT, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Permissions, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Techtopia NVTC Map, May 2007 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Tysons Contract 5/2007, May 2007 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Publicity, May 2007 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Ox Hill, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Illustrations, 2002-2006 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Watershed Map, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Maps Tysons Dulles Corridor, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Copies of material from 1958-1992
  - Tysons Maps with Federal Offices and Greater Metro Area (1 of 2), 2007 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Tysons Maps (2 of 2), 2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Research Notes, circa 2000s (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - House Committee Reports, circa 2000s (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Copies of material from 1960s
  - Tech Growth in Tyson's Corner Area (1 of 2), 2001-2007 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Tech Growth in Tyson's Corner Area (2 of 2), 2001-2007 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Cole, Noman Report, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "How Big Money Changed Washington", 2006 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Referee Reports, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Secondary Sources (1 of 2), 1998-2003 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Secondary Sources (2 of 2), 1991, 2000-2006 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Research Primary Sources 1960s, circa 2000s (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Business History in Tysons (1 of 2), 2000-2006 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Business History in Tysons (2 of 2), 2000-2006 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Outlines, Sept. 2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Beltway Region Cold War History, 1997-2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Development of the Beltway, 1992-2003 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Declassified Military Docs, 2001-2004 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Copies of material from 1960s-1980s
  - Fox, Justin Time Mag 2/19/2007, Feb. 2007 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - e-mails, Aug. 1999-Mar. 2000 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Greenbelt 1930s-1950s, July 2000 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Contains photos
  - Columbia, circa 2000 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Copies of material from 1968-1969, 1990-1995
  - Ceruzzi, Photo, circa 2000 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - DC History (1 of 3), 2000-2005 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - DC History (2 of 3), 1999-2003 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - DC History (3 of 3), 1987-2005 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Tech and Development in Fairfax, 1990-2003 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Business Growth in Fairfax, 1994-2005 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Internet History and Draft, 2003-2006 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - History of Tysons Corner and Edge Cities, circa 2000 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Growth of Fairfax, 1994-2004 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - VA Industry, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Growth of Networking Research, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Economic Growth in Greater Washington, 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Audio Interview Recordings, 2000-2004 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Recordings on cassette tape. Includes interview with George Johnson.
  - Binder Photo Negatives and Slides (1 of 3), 1980s-2003 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Contains negatives, slides and digital CD
  - Binder Newspapers (2 of 3), 1994, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Binder Research Reports and Journals on Military-Industrial History (3 of 3), 1992-2003 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings - Technology, circa 1990s (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Copies of material from 1954-1988
  - BDM Annual Reports (1 of 5), 1987, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - BDM Annual Reports (2 of 5), 1994-1996, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - BDM Annual Reports (3 of 5), 1977-1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - BDM Annual Reports (4 of 5), 1981-1984 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - BDM Annual Reports (5 of 5), 1985-1987 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Accenture, Dec. 2004 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - ADAPSO Interview, May 2001 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - ADAPSO May 2002 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - ADAPSO Story, Mar. 1970 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - AEC Germantown, circa 1990s (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Aerospace Industry Consolidation, Dec. 1996 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Aerospace Corp., Jan. 2003 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - AIAA, March 2005 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - RADAR - AIL, 1990-1992 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - AJCC, etc, 2003-2004 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Amazon Data Center ASHBURN, April 2011 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - AMS, 1997-2004 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 4S Popular History of the Internet, November 2005 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Analytical Service, Anser, 2003-2004 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Copies of material from 1963, 2003-2004
  - Anderson, Douglas T, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - AOL (1 of 2), 1998 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - AOL (2 of 2), 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Apple Retail Store, June 2003 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Covers 2001
  - ARINC, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Arlington, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Arlington Museum, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Armor Group North, Sept. 2009 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - ARPA, Apr. 2003 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Atlantic Research, 2003-2004 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Atwood Nat Geo, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Backbone, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Bailey Crossroads, 2002-2004 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - BBN, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Errata Utilization Report, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    Written by Lavagnino
  - Williams, Earle (1 of 2), 1990-2000 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Williams, Earle (2 of 2), 1985, 1998-2000 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Corporate PR, 1992-1999 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - BDM Employees, circa 1999 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Employed during the 1960s
  - BDM Interviews with Founders, 1997, 2016 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    2016 is obituary for one of the founders
  - BDM History, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Covers 1970s-1990s
  - Lavagnino, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Materials date 1960s-1980s
  - BDM Physics, circa 1992 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Covers circa 1980s
  - Control Data Corporation - CDC (1 of 2), 1968-1973 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - CDC (2 of 2), 2003 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - CACI International Incorporated, 2000-2005 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - CACI 2009 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Cable and Wireless, 2006-2009 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Butrica, Andrew, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - BTG, Inc, 1997-2002 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Brown Bag Lunch Presentation, June 17, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Brody, Sam, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Bright, Christopher, 2000-2004 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Bowman Distillery, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Boucher 1992, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Borders, November 11, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Booz-Allen and Hamilton, 1997-2004 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Boncek, Andrew, May 2002 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - BITNET, 1991-1996 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Bell, Gordon 1995 Interview Transcript, May 4, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Beltway HOT Lanes, July 2008 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Beltway Bandits Flyball Club [sic], October 2000 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Board of Trade, greater Washington, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Transportation study
  - BDM stock information and merger with Ford, 1986-1988 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - BDM Employment and Contract Report, 1960, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - BDM Reports, 1962-1983 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Mathematics and Technological Manuals, circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Journal of Aeronautical Sciences, Volume 18, Number 9, September 1951 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Quality Control and Reliability Handbook, April 29, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - BDM Organization and Professional Staff, circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Technical Manuals, 1945, 1982-1985 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - BDM List of Projects (1 of 3), circa 1993-1997 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - BDM List of Projects (2 of 3), circa 1993-1997 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - BDM List of Projects (3 of 3), circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Mathematics and Physics (1 of 2), circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Mathematics and Physics (2 of 2), circa 1970s (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - BDM Missile Research Reports, 1961-1964 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - NASA Direction Cosine Reports, March-September 1969 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Photometry, 1957-1970s (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Bendix Gyro Information, Fall 1967 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - MIRV - Working Papers, circa 1960s (Box 11, Folder 2)
    Contains map of White Sands Missile Range
  - Estimation Theory and Transistorized Module Guide, 1957-circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Chapin, Peter, 2002 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Cerf, Vinton, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - CEIR (Council for Economic and Industrial Research), 2004-2005 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Civil War in Northern Virginia, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - CIA Science and Tech, circa 2000s (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - CIA - West Branch, Jones Branch, 1999-2003 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - CIA (1 of 2), 2003-2004 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - CIA (2 of 2), 1993-1995 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - CIA/SAG, November 22, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Center for Innovative Technology (CIT), 2000-2005 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - CIX Router, circa 2006 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Cleveland, James Interview, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - CNRI - Corporation for National Research Initiatives, 1987-2005 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - CNRI (Kahn), 2006 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Cogent Communications, December 2005 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Coleman, William (Secretary of Transportation 1977), circa 2000s (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Columbia, Maryland, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Combes, Richard (Atlanta High-Tech), 2001 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - National Commission on the Future of the United States Aerospace Industry, circa 2005 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Company Listings, 2002-2003 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Commerce Business Daily, 2003-2004 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Competition in Contracting Act, 1984, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Connoly, Interview, 2005 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Coopley, edited, November 2004 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Cortright and Mayer, January 2001 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Conferences 2003/4, 2003-2004 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Crandall, Rick, circa 2001 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Computer Sciences Corporation (CSC), 1999-2008 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Danoff, Clarence [sic], circa 2000s (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - CTC Communications, October 2005 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - DC Freeway Plan, Inner Beltway, March 2003 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - DeNardis, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Doman Name Servers, 1998-2005 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Dreicer, Greg, March 2003 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Dulles (Town) Airport, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Dulles Access Road Toll Road, I-66, 2003, 2009 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Dulles, Airport, 2005 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - DynCorp, 1998-2008 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Erros, etc. New Edition/Printing, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Fairfax County, Virginia. Library and Chamber of Commerce, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Fairfax County Trail, 2006 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR), 2004 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - FAS, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Feldman, Maryann, circa 2000s (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Federally Funded Research and Development Center (FFRDC), 2003 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Fishbein, Samuel, November 7, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Foreign Editions, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Foundry, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Fort Detrick, 2004 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Fuller, Steven, October 2001 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Gannett/USA Today, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Garfinkel (1996), December 2005 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Garreau, Joel, 2008 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - GE Information Services, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Glossbrenner, Alfred, circa 1990s (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - George Mason University, 1998-2004 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Gore, Al, 2006 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Graboske, Trish, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - GRC International, 1994-2000 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - George Washington University 10/2000, October 2000 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Halpin, Gerald T., March 2003 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Hanssen, Robert P, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Grier, David Allen, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Hazel, Til, 1997-2000 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Herndon, circa 2000s (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Herrity, John F, 2003-2006 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Hessler, Martina Deutsche Museum, Munich Study 2002 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Homeland Security, January 2003 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Hopper, Grace Park, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Howard Hughes, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - ICAAN/InterNIC (Internet Network Information Center), July 2005 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - ICC, July 2005 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Interstate 66, March 2003 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Tysons Corner: Image of America Series, 2005-2010 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Institute for Defense Analysis, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Internet, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Internet Society, A Brief History, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Intellilink, November 2005 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Jaycor, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Job Faire, January 2004 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - John Hopkins [sic], 1992-1994 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Johnson, George W., March 2004 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Kahn, Robert Interview, 1999-2002 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Katz, Peter Emails, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Kentlands, 2000-2003 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Kesan and Shah Privatization of Internet Backbone, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Kiefer, Jerry, 2000, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Korr, Jeremy, 2000-2002 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Kraemer, Sylvia George Mason University, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Krammer, Joan, 2002-2003 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Journal of Military History, May 2004 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Mel Kranzberg Papers, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Krol, Hitchhiker's Guide to the Internet RFC 118, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Knowledge, Technology and Policy Paper (KTP), 2000 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - KTP Proposal, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - L3 Communications Corporation, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Lang, Edgeless Cities, 1997-2004 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - The Last Supper, 1993-2004 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Lemelson, 2005-2006 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Level 3, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Lewis, Roger, 2001, 2008 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Light, Jennifer S. Urban Defense Conversion, September 2002 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Living Internet.com Architecture, November 2005 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - LCC Inc., 1995 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Loral/Lockheed Martin, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - L.L. Bean, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Lowe, Thaddeus 1832-1813, circa 2000s (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - MAE East (Metropolitan Area Exchange), 2003 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - MAE, FIX, NAP (Network Access Point) etc, 2006-2008 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - MAE East 1919 Gallows Road, 2005-2006 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - MAE East/Tom Davis, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - MacGillis, Alec, 2007 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - MAN Tech, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Marine, April, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Mastran, Shelley, May 2000 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Mayer, Heike "Silicon Forest", April 2004 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - MCI/Worldcom/VVNet, 2002-2005 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Melpar, 1994-2007 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - MicroStrategy, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 2007-2016 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - MIT Press, 2005-2006 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Mitre, 1995-2009 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Maryland-National Capital Park and Planning Commission (MNCPPC), December 2005 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Morino Institute, 2000-2003 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Morino, Mario OHI 2003 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Morris Worm, 1988, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - MHz Network (TV Station), 2003 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) Archives, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - MIT Lincoln Laboratory, circa 2001 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Monorails, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Moore, Audrey, 2003-2005 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Morr, Thomas, March 2003 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Morse, Philip (MIT Archives), July 2001 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Mount Weather, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Mueller, Ruling the Root, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - National Air and Space Museum (NASM) Internet, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - National Archives, circa 2000s (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - NARA - Signal Corp - Tyson Tower AJCC, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - NASM Style Manual, October 2001 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Naval Medical Center, Bethesda, March 2005 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Network Solutions, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - NBS, January 2003 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - National Museum of American History Tuesday Colloquium, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Northrop Grumman, November 2006 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - NSA (National Security Agency), 2000 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - National Reconnaissance Office (NRO), 2001 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Numbers Stations, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) Proposal on Internet Douglas Gale, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - NSF Net History, 2005 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Otto Kroeger Associates (OKA), 2001 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Northern Virginia Technology Council (NVTC), 2001-2008 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Oracle, November 2006 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Circular A-76. circa 1960s-2003 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Orbitaz, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - ORO, Chevy Chase, circa 1990s (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Peninsular and Oriental Lines, December 2006 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Pearlstein 2007, March 2007 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - September 11 - Pentagon, August 2003 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Peter, Ian "So, Who Invented..", November 2005 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Photography - Rights, circa 2003-2005 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Pimmit Run?, circa 2002 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Plummers Island, November 2003 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Postel, Jonathan, December 2005 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Planning Research Corporation (PRC)/Litton, 1998-2000, 2009 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - PRC, 1990-2000 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Prodigy, June 2006 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Professional Services Conference, 2008-2009 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Professional Services Council (PSC), October 2000 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Book Proposal, March 23, 2006 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Planning Systems Inc. (PSI), 1997, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - PSI-NET, 1996-2005 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Publicity and Marketing, 2008 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Qwest, February 2006 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Rand, 1983-2003 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Rau, Erik, 1999-2000 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - RDB, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Release 1.0, September 2003 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Research Analysis Corporation (JHU) (Johns Hopkins University), 2000-2003 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Reston, 1999-2000 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Red Herring Research, October 2002 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Rochen, Herb, October 2000 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Rutgers University Press, 1996-2005 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Author Guidelines for Rutgers, 2003-2005 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Ruttan, Vernon, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Science Applications International Corporation (SAIC) (1 of 2), 1996-2006 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - SAIC (2 of 2), 1997-2004 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Salus, Peter Groklaw, May 2006 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Scott's Run, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Sensitive Compartmented Information Facilities (SCIF) Solutions, 2003-2004 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Systems Development Corporation (SDC), circa 2000s (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - SDI, May 2005 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Section 8(a), 2004 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Shane, Scott New York Times, February 2007 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Fiber Capacity Sharon, Mike, 2003-2004 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Shubin, Lester Interview, 2000 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Silver Spring, September 2008 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Smithsonian, September 1996 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Society for Military History Bethesda, May 2004 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Site R, October 2006 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    Raven Rock Mountain Complex
  - Society for Military History Paper Presentation, May 2004 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Synchronus Optical Network (SONET), December 2005 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - The Source, April 2003 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Project SQUID, April 2004 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - SRA International Incorporated (SRA), 1997-2005 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Sugar Grove, 2003-2005 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Sully Plantation, circa 2000 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Supercomputer Research Center, 2003 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - SURAnet (Southeastern Universities Research Association), 2006 (Box 21, Folder 8)